Henry Wang

Software Engineer

Phone

(647) 518-2906

E-mail

henry-h.wang@hotmail.com

SKILLS

- Java
 - JavaFX
- Python
 - TensorFlow
 - MediaPipe
- JavaScript
 - o Next.js
- HTML/CSS
 - Tailwind CSS
- SQL

ACADEMIC COMPETITIONS

- Alnnovation (2023)
- Western Engineering Competition (2024)
- Canadian Undergraduate
 Conference on Artificial
 Intellegiance (2024)
- Toronto Tech Expo (2024)

AWARDS

- Social Good Award at Toronto Tech Expo (2024)
- Western Scholarship of Distinction (2022)
- Seven total scholarships from the University Settlement Music and Arts School for exceptional piano performance (2015-2022)

Second year Software Engineering student attending the University of Western Ontario with 6+ years of programming experience. A logical and detail-oriented programmer who works well in stressful environments with years of backend development and some Al development experience.

Work Experience

Piano Tutor

Self-employed, Scarborough, ON

Aug 2022 - July 2023

- Conducted individual lessons lasting from 60 to 120 minutes each.
- Established strong music foundation with students by incorporating basic music theory into weekly lessons.
- Communicated regularly with parents to provide information about children's progress and challenges.

Frontend Web Developer

Predictify Pro, Scarborough, ON

May 2024 - Current

- · Designed and developed the company's main website using Next.js, Tailwind CSS, and HTML.
- Worked with the founder and other developers to meet the founder's expectations and fulfil deadlines.

Education

International Baccalaureate Diploma

Victoria Park Collegiate Institute - Toronto, ON

Sept 2018 - June 2022

• Final score: 41/45

Bachelor of Engineering Science: Software Engineering

University of Western Ontario - London, ON

Sept 2022 - Current

4.0/4.0 (92%) CGPA

Projects

- Developed a sample-tracking database software for a genetic research laboratory at the University of Toronto, creating a more efficient workflow for researchers.
- Developed an American Sign Language to English translator and educator web application along with a team of seven developers for Western Cyber Society, using machine learning and computer vision.
 - Lead the development for the ASL hand gesture recognition machine learning model, helping train 60+ signs to be recognized by the model.
 - Presented the project to be judged by industry professionals at Toronto Tech Expo, winning the Social Good Award.

Extracurriculars.

- Over 12 years of piano playing experience, performing in numerous concerts and competitions.
- Over 8 years of percussion playing experience in orchestra, performing in concerts and competitions.
- Current member and percussion player for Western Chamber Music.

